<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="8" moduleid="113" modulename="folder" contextid="226">
  <folder id="8">
    <name>Functions of Management: Introduction</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While managers often view their work as task or supervisory in orientation, this view is an illusion.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the most fundamental level, management is a discipline that consists of a set of five general functions: planning, organizing, staffing, leading and controlling. These five functions are part of a body of practices and theories on how to be a successful manager.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Understanding the functions will help managers focus efforts on activities that gain results.&amp;nbsp;Summarizing the five functions of great management (ICPM Management Content):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Planning:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;When you think of planning in a management role, think about it as the process of choosing appropriate goals and actions to pursue and then determining what strategies to use, what actions to take, and deciding what resources are needed to achieve the goals.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organizing:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;This process of establishing worker relationships allows workers to work together to achieve their organizational goals.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leading:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;This function involves articulating a vision, energizing employees, inspiring and motivating people using vision, influence, persuasion, and effective communication skills&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Staffing:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Recruiting and selecting employees for positions within the company (within teams and departments).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controlling:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Evaluate how well you are achieving your goals, improving performance, taking actions. Put processes in place to help you establish standards, so you can measure, compare, and make decisions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <revision>3</revision>
    <timemodified>1654864880</timemodified>
    <display>0</display>
    <showexpanded>0</showexpanded>
    <showdownloadfolder>0</showdownloadfolder>
    <forcedownload>1</forcedownload>
  </folder>
</activity>