<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="10" moduleid="115" modulename="folder" contextid="228">
  <folder id="10">
    <name>Importance of Management</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;Introduction to Management is not a hard science. Unlike chemistry or algebra where a right answer (often) exists, management is fluid, and subjective, and there are divergent perspectives on how to employ its principles.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;But what exactly is management? Most scholars have variations of the same definition that include a utilization of resources to achieve a goal.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;Lussier (2021) defines a manager as “the individual responsible for achieving organizational objectives through efficient and effective utilization of resources” (p. 3). The problem with this definition is that it implies that a manager has to be both efficient and effective, which eliminates the possibility of having a bad manager. Each of us can probably contradict this definition by providing an example from our personal past. However, this definition contains the basic elements of using resources to pursue goals.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;An early management scholar, Mary P. Follett characterized management as “the art of getting things done through the efforts of other people” (Graham, 1995). This definition implies both pursuing goals (getting things done) and utilizing resources (predominantly through people). However, this too is missing an element, that of the organizational context. An important consideration for understanding management is that the term organization simply refers to “a collection of people working together to achieve a common purpose” (Shermerhorn, 2013, p. 11). This means an organization could be anything from your high school volleyball team to church or a corporation. Including the term “organization” in the definition leaves open the possibility that management can be practiced in each of these settings, and broadens our use of the term management. A comprehensive definition for management then, would be the pursuit of organizational goals through the use of organizational resources (Bateman &amp;amp; Snell, 2013).&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <revision>1</revision>
    <timemodified>1654865431</timemodified>
    <display>0</display>
    <showexpanded>0</showexpanded>
    <showdownloadfolder>0</showdownloadfolder>
    <forcedownload>0</forcedownload>
  </folder>
</activity>